johnfrieda.com 2019-03-10

# Privacy Policy | John Frieda

Kao USA Inc. ("Kao") Privacy Policy

  At Kao, we respect your privacy and take reasonable measures to protect your privacy. This policy applies only to the website on which it appears, and does not apply to any other Kao websites or services.  By accessing or using this website, you agree and consent to our use of your information as described in this policy.   

EFFECTIVE DATE  
This privacy policy is effective and was last updated on April 12, 2017. 

WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU  
Personally Identifiable Information  
This website is structured so that, in general, you can visit without revealing any personally identifiable information. Once you choose to provide us with such information, you may be assured that it will only be used in accordance with the principles set forth in this document.  

  On some Kao web pages, you can interact with entry forms for the purposes of contacting us, subscribing to communications, registering for an account, engaging in promotional events or other purposes. The types of personally identifiable information collected at these pages may include name, mailing address and email address. We may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products, and contact preferences. 

  We do not collect any personally identifiable information from you through this website unless you provide it to us. If you email us or answer questions we have placed on this website, you are voluntarily releasing that information to us for use as set forth in this policy. Please do not submit personally identifiable information to us if you do not want us to have this information in our database.  

  Performance Information  
Kao may record your interactions with our advertisements, our websites, emails or other applications we provide using Clickstream Data and Cookies. “Clickstream Data” is a recording of what you click on while browsing this website. This data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the website from which you linked to this website. 

  “Cookies” are small text files that are placed on your computer by a website for the purpose of facilitating and enhancing your communication and interaction with that website, remembering your preferences and collecting aggregate (i.e., not personally identifiable) information. Many websites, including ours, use cookies for these purposes.

  The website may also include cookies set by third parties, including Adobe Analytics (a service available from the web analysis provider Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited (“Adobe”), which 1) helps us measure the performance of the website, 2) allows us to share relevant information and advertising with you based on your and other visitors’ past visits to this website when you surf the web, and 3) helps us measure your interactions with any Kao advertising you see on other sites.  Finally, Kao will use data from Adobe’s interest-based advertising or third-party audience data, such as age, gender and interests, together with our own data, to deliver relevant advertising to you based upon your demographic profile and interests.    

  You can opt-out of Adobe Analytics by using the Adobe Analytics opt-out Browser add-on at http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html.  You can find more information about Adobe Analytics here.

  You may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or flush them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences and browser plug-in settings, in which case you may still use our website, but it may interfere with some of its functionality.  

  Information from children  
Kao has no intention of collecting personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. Kao will maintain procedures to assure that personally identifiable information about children under the age of 13 is only collected with explicit consent of such child’s parent or guardian. If a child under the age of 13 has provided Kao with personally identifiable information without such consent, Kao asks that a parent or guardian of the child contact Kao using our Contact Us page to inform us of that fact. Kao will use reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database. 

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION  
Kao uses your information to understand your needs and provide better products and services. Kao may use data collected from you to personalize your website experience, tailor future communications, and send you targeted offers as described below. Occasionally, Kao may use your personally identifiable information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. We will always give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such contacts.  

  Kao may share the personally identifiable information you provide with other Kao divisions or affiliates, provided that, such other divisions or affiliates have privacy practices that are similar to those set forth in this policy.  

  Kao may permit its vendors and subcontractors to access your personally identifiable information, but they are only permitted to do so in connection with services they are performing for Kao. They are not authorized by Kao to use your personally identifiable information for their own benefit. Kao may disclose personally identifiable information as required by law or legal process.  

  Kao may disclose personally identifiable information to investigate suspected fraud, harassment or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, or the terms or policies for the website. 

  In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution, reorganization or acquisition of Kao, or a Kao business unit, information Kao has collected about you may be sold or otherwise transferred. However, this will only happen if the party acquiring the information agrees to use personally identifiable information in a manner which is substantially similar to the uses described in this policy.  

  Sweepstakes, contests and other promotions may set forth additional uses of your personally identifiable information in connection with such promotions.  

  THIRD PARTY COLLECTION AND SHARING  
At times, personally identifiable information may be collected from you on behalf of Kao and a third party who is identified at the time of collection. This may include co-branded promotions. In such instances, your personally identifiable information may be provided to both Kao and such third party. While Kao will use your personally identifiable information as set forth in this policy, such third party will use your personally identifiable information as set forth in their own privacy policy. Such third parties may collect information regarding your activities over time and across different websites.  Therefore, you should review such policies prior to providing your personally identifiable information. Kao is not responsible for the actions of such third parties.  

TARGETED CONTENT AND MESSAGING  
We believe that content, messages and advertising are more relevant and valuable to you when they are based upon your interests, needs and demographics. Therefore, we may deliver content, messages and advertising specifically to you that are based upon your prior activities on our websites and information provided to us or gathered as described in this policy. For example, if you have previously expressed an interest in hair care products through your activities on our website, we may deliver more information to you about hair care products than other products for which you have not expressed an interest or interacted with on the website. While we may use this information to tailor what we deliver to you, we will still handle and secure your personally identifiable information as set forth in this policy.  

  Through the use of the Adobe services (described above), the cookies we place on this website, and cookies placed by third parties on this website or through other sites you visit on the internet, we may cause advertisements and content to appear on this website and elsewhere on the internet based upon your activities over time and across different websites.  In most instances, Kao is simply a content provider and does not directly possess such behavioral information about your online activities.  You are able to limit such targeted advertising by setting your browser to block third party cookies or by visiting www.aboutads.info/choices to learn more about such advertising practices and to exercise options with respect to such practices at www.aboutads.info/choices.  

  We do not respond to or honor “do not track” (a/k/a DNT) signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers.  

SOCIAL MEDIA PLUGINS  
The website may use social plugins (“plugins”) of various social networks. The integration of these plugins provides the respective social network with the information that you have accessed the linked page of our website. If you are logged into the pertinent social network, it has the capability to allocate this visit to your user account. If you are actively using the plugins (for example, the “Like” button on Facebook), the related information is directly transferred to the social network by your browser and is subsequently stored there. If you do not want the social network to collect data about you via the Kao website, you will have to log out of these networks before your visit the website. However, even if you are not logged into a social network when you visit the website, it is possible for websites with active social plugins to send data to the social networks. The social plugin places a cookie with identification data every time the website is accessed, making it possible that this identification data can later be allocated to a person (e.g., if you log into the social network later). If you do not want social networks to collect data about you through active plugins, you can choose the “block third party cookies” option under your browser settings. However, choosing this setting may also cause other site-wide functions besides the plugins not to work under certain circumstances. We use the following plugins on our websites: Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, YouTube and Instagram.   
Facebook  
We use the plugins of social network facebook.com, operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The link to Facebook’s data privacy declaration can be found here: Data Privacy Information Facebook. 

Twitter  
We use the plugins of social network twitter.com, operated by Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103 U.S.A. (“Twitter”). The link to Twitter’s data privacy declaration can be found here:  Data Privacy Information Twitter  

Pinterest  
We use the plugins of social network Pinterest, operated by Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, USA (“Pinterest”). The link to Pinterest’s data privacy declaration can be found here: Data Privacy Information Pinterest.

Youtube  
We use the plugins of the Youtube website, operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“Youtube”). The link to YouTube’s data privacy declaration can be found here:  Data Privacy Information YouTube. 

Instagram  
We use the plugins of social network Instagram, operated by Instagram, LLC Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA (“Instagram”). The link to Instagram’s data privacy declaration can be found here:  Data Privacy Information Instagram.

YOUR CHOICE  
Kao will not use or share the information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described in this policy without letting you know and offering you a choice.

  LINKS TO OTHER SITES  
This website may contain links to other websites and services.  This can include clicking “Buy Now” or a similar feature to take you to the websites of various third party retailers where you can browse or purchase Kao products.  We do not control such third party websites and services and are not responsible for their actions or privacy practices.  The existence of a link on our website does not mean that we endorse or have vetted such third party website or service.  You are encouraged to carefully review the policies and practices of every website and service that you visit. 

SECURITY  
Kao is committed to taking reasonable steps to ensure the security of the information we collect. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personally identifiable information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the personally identifiable information we collect online. If we provide you a direct means for maintaining your information in our database, such as through a “profile center” application, you are responsible for taking reasonable precautions to protect your login data, such ID and password. Kao will not be responsible for breach that results from a lost or stolen login.

NON-CONFIDENTIAL  
Any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions, or the like is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary. Except to the extent expressly covered by this policy, anything you transmit or post may be used by us for any purpose, including but not limited to, reproduction, disclosure, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. You expressly agree that we are free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, or techniques contained in any communication you send to us without compensation and for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products and services using such information. Furthermore, you confirm that any media files you submit to us (eg. pictures, videos, etc) are your property and you have permission of anyone depicted in these files to transfer rights to Kao. 

ACCESS TO AND CORRECTION OF INFORMATION / OPT-OUT  
Kao will maintain reasonable procedures for individuals to gain access to their personally identifiable information and preferences. Kao will correct any information that is inaccurate or incomplete or allow you to change your individual consent level. You may do so by contacting us with the relevant details for your request.   
If you wish for us to stop using your personally identifiable information and delete it from our list of active users, please contact us with the details necessary to complete your request. We will process and honor such requests within a reasonable period of time after receipt. However, even though we may remove your personally identifiable information from our list of active users, we are not responsible for removing your personally identifiable information from the lists of any third party who has been provided your information in accordance with this policy, such as a business partner.  
As described above, you are able to opt-out of certain targeted advertising by setting your browser to block third party cookies or by visitingwww.aboutads.info/choices. 

DATA RETENTION  
Except as described in the section above, we may retain and continue to use information collected under this privacy policy for as long as we have a business need for such information. 

COMMENT AND QUESTIONS  
If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy or your personally identifiable information, please use our Contact Us page. 

UNITED STATES OF AMERICA  
This website and our related databases are maintained in the United States of America. By using the website, you freely and specifically give us your consent to collect and store your information in the United States and to use your information as specified within this policy. 

CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY  
Kao will, and reserves the right to, modify and update this policy or its related business practices at any time at our discretion. Any such material changes will be posted here for reference. However, Kao will not make material changes to this policy, such as how it discloses personally identifiable information, without giving you a chance to opt-out of such differing uses. Your continued use of the website following the posting of any changes to this privacy policy means you accept such changes.
